{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Disco","incorrectAnswers":["Grunge","Hippie","Preppy"],"question":"What is the name of the fashion trend popularized in the 1970s that involves wearing bell-bottoms, platform shoes, and oversized shirts?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Books, printing, and publishing","incorrectAnswers":["The shape of a person's skull","Pilates","Prehistoric life"],"question":"What is Bibliology the study of?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Holes","incorrectAnswers":["The Giver","To Kill a Mockingbird","The Hunger Games"],"question":"Which chapter of the novel by Louis Sachar begins with the line 'There is no lake at Camp Green Lake'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"The v in 'village'","incorrectAnswers":["The y in 'yellow'","The k in 'sock'","The r in 'red'"],"question":"In phonetics, which of these is an example of a fricative sound?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Saxophone","incorrectAnswers":["Piano","Drums","Violin"],"question":"With Which Particular Instrument Would You Associate Gerry Mulligan?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Buck","incorrectAnswers":["A Rooster","A Ram","A Stallion"],"question":"What is the word for a male weasel?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Toy Story","incorrectAnswers":["Pan's Labyrinth","The Exorcist","Gandhi"],"question":"Name the movie that matches the following plot summary: 'A cowboy doll is threatened when a new spaceman figure supplants him as top toy.'","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Matthew McConaughey","incorrectAnswers":["Ryan Reynolds","Jim Carrey","Hugh Jackman"],"question":"Which Hollywood actor has starred in films including Interstellar and The Wolf of Wall Street?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"The Tuxedo","incorrectAnswers":["The Wristwatch","Sneakers","Denim Jeans"],"question":"What was first worn in the 1860's?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Samsung","incorrectAnswers":["Vodafone","PlayStation","Google"],"question":"'Everyone's invited' is a slogan associated with which technology brand?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Dustin Hoffman","incorrectAnswers":["Robert Duvall","Michael Douglas","Kevin Spacey"],"question":"Which actor played the role of Raymond Babbitt in Rain Man?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Suzanne Collins","incorrectAnswers":["Frederik Pohl","Dan Brown","Philip K. Dick"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Catching Fire'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"As You Like It","incorrectAnswers":["A Midsummer Night's Dream","The Tempest","Hamlet"],"question":"In which of Shakespeare's plays do we find the famous line 'All the world's a stage'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Realism","incorrectAnswers":["Dutch and Flemish Renaissance","Primitivism","Fauvism"],"question":"The painting \"The Gleaners\" by Jean-François Millet is a part of which art movement?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Sole","incorrectAnswers":["Heel","Arch","Instep"],"question":"What is the name for the undersurface of a foot?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Who","incorrectAnswers":["Deep Purple","Travis","Spandau Ballet"],"question":"Which English rock band released the song 'My Generation'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Edvard Munch","incorrectAnswers":["Otto Dix","Anita Malfatti","Franz Marc"],"question":"\"The Scream\" was painted by which artist?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Sardine","incorrectAnswers":["Broccoli","Beef","Peanuts"],"question":"Which of these foods is a good source of omega-3 fatty acids?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Hermès","incorrectAnswers":["Smirnoff","Linux","Peugeot"],"question":"Which of these brands has a horse on its logo?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Kinks","incorrectAnswers":["Deep Purple","Snow Patrol","Lostprophets"],"question":"Which English rock band released the song 'You Really Got Me'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"West Germany","incorrectAnswers":["Spain","Italy","Uruguay"],"question":"Which country won the 1974 FIFA World Cup, hosted in West Germany?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Robert A. Heinlein","incorrectAnswers":["Edgar Rice Burroughs","George R. R. Martin","Jack Vance"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Starship Troopers'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Robots","incorrectAnswers":["Aliens","Gods","Wizards"],"question":"Transformers are ___________ in disguise. ","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"The Atlas Mountains","incorrectAnswers":["The Rocky Mountains","The Andes","The Himalayas"],"question":"What mountain range is next to a region once known as the Barbary Coast?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Caddyshack","incorrectAnswers":["The Godfather","A Clockwork Orange","The Silence of the Lambs"],"question":"Which film contains the character 'Carl Spackler'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Indo-European","incorrectAnswers":["Koreanic","Afroasiatic","Sino-Tibetan"],"question":"The language 'Italian' belongs to which language family?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Sagrada Familia","incorrectAnswers":["Palau de la Musica Catalana","Basilica de la Merce","Palau Guell"],"question":"What is the name of the iconic Gaudi building located in Barcelona?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"A Discus","incorrectAnswers":["An arrow","A lightning bolt","A bottle of wine"],"question":"The Greek God Apollo Accidently Killed His Friend Hyacinthus with what?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Afroasiatic","incorrectAnswers":["Indo-European","Koreanic","Dravidian"],"question":"The language 'Somali' belongs to which language family?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Feet","incorrectAnswers":["Backs","Teeth","Knees"],"question":"What Does A Chiropodist Treat","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"After all, tomorrow is another day!\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"Here's Johnny!\"","\"Take your stinking paws off me, you damned dirty ape.\"","\"You shall not pass!\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'Gone with the Wind'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Citroën","incorrectAnswers":["Toyota","Honda","Opel"],"question":"Which car manufacturer made the DS19?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"A Mexican state","incorrectAnswers":["A Mexican folk hero","A Mexican dish","A Mexican desert"],"question":"What is the Chihuahua named after?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"A free black man from upstate New York is abducted and sold.","incorrectAnswers":["The son of a city's mastermind falls in love with a working-class prophet.","A young F.B.I. cadet must receive the help of a cannibal to help catch another serial killer.","A kindhearted street urchin and a power-hungry Grand Vizier vie for a magic lamp."],"question":"What is the plot of the movie 12 Years a Slave?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"South Korea","incorrectAnswers":["Taiwan","China","Japan"],"question":"In which country is the company Daewoo based?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Vitamin C","incorrectAnswers":["Vitamin D","Vitamin A","Vitamin B"],"question":"Ascorbic acid is commonly referred to as which vitamin?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"The Game of Life","incorrectAnswers":["Risk","Monopoly","Clue"],"question":"What is the name of the classic board game where players race through a person's life from childhood to retirement?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Matthew McConaughey","incorrectAnswers":["Ryan Reynolds","Jim Carrey","Hugh Jackman"],"question":"Which actor has played prominent roles in films including The Wolf of Wall Street and Dallas Buyers Club?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Sino-Tibetan","incorrectAnswers":["Afroasiatic","Dravidian","Kra–Dai"],"question":"The language 'Xiang Chinese' belongs to which language family?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"1994","incorrectAnswers":["1999","1989","1984"],"question":"In which year did the show 'Friends' first air?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Roman","incorrectAnswers":["Greek","Persian","Egyptian"],"question":"Which empire put down a revolt led by Vercingetorix in 52 B.C.?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Romeo","incorrectAnswers":["Tybalt","Mercutio","Paris"],"question":"Which character in Romeo & Juliet totally forgets about his crush on Rosaline and falls in love with Juliet?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Peter The Great","incorrectAnswers":["Ivan The Terrible","Catherine The Great","Ivan The Great"],"question":"Who was the great czar who led Russia to victory against Charles XII of Sweden in The Great Northern War of 1700-1721?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Harry Potter","incorrectAnswers":["Goosebumps","Percy Jackson & the Olympians","Twilight"],"question":"In which book series does 'Hermione Granger' appear?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Queen","incorrectAnswers":["Level 42","Deep Purple","Feeder"],"question":"Which British rock band released the song 'The Show Must Go On'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"George III","incorrectAnswers":["George IV","William IV","Victoria"],"question":"Which British monarch reigned during the American War of Independence (1775-1783)?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Vietnam","incorrectAnswers":["Bangladesh","Cambodia","South Korea"],"question":"Where would you find the city of Hanoi?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Laos","incorrectAnswers":["Mozambique","Brazil","Zambia"],"question":"Vientiane is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The Tower of London","incorrectAnswers":["Windsor Castle","Buckingham Palace","St. James's Palace"],"question":"What is the name of the royal fortress on the Thames River that includes Traitors' Gate?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Peru","incorrectAnswers":["Tanzania","Thailand","Australia"],"question":"In which country would you find Machu Picchu?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Apple","incorrectAnswers":["Grape","Plum","Banana"],"question":"James Grieve and Egremont Russet are types of which fruit?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Chisinau","incorrectAnswers":["Kinshasa","Lusaka","Tallinn"],"question":"What is the capital city of Moldova?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Tubular ","incorrectAnswers":["Anulus","Spiral","Shell"],"question":"What shape is macaroni?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Itinerary","incorrectAnswers":["List","Voyage","Menu"],"question":"What is the term for a list of places to visit on a journey?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Luge","incorrectAnswers":["Bobs","Trok","Aski"],"question":"What is the word for a racing sled?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Jean Dujardin","incorrectAnswers":["Demián Bichir","George Clooney","Gary Oldman"],"question":"Who won the 2011 Academy Award for Best Leading Actor for playing the role of George Valentin in The Artist?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Medellin","incorrectAnswers":["Buenos Aires","Salvador","Valparaíso"],"question":"Which of these cities is in Colombia?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"William Shakespeare","incorrectAnswers":["Arthur C. Clarke","Isaac Newton","Enid Blyton"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Julius Caesar'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Belarus","incorrectAnswers":["Kyrgyzstan","Tajikistan","Ukraine"],"question":"Where would you find the city of Minsk?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Yanka Kupala","incorrectAnswers":["Nikolai Gogol","Vladimir Nabokov","Henryk Sienkiewicz"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Huśliar'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Velvet Underground","incorrectAnswers":["The Beatles","Talking Heads","The Doors"],"question":"Which band did the German singer Nico collaborate with on a 1967 album?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Bat","incorrectAnswers":["Lion","Horse","Crocodile"],"question":"Which animal would you associate with the Bacardi logo?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Malta","incorrectAnswers":["Croatia","Turkey","Tanzania"],"question":"In which country would you find the UNESCO World Heritage site of Valletta?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Russia","incorrectAnswers":["France","United States","England"],"question":"Which country hosted the 2018 FIFA World Cup?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"The Quiet American","incorrectAnswers":["The Swimmer","Tinker","The World According to Garp"],"question":"Which book contains the character 'Alden Pyle'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A gaggle","incorrectAnswers":["A nest","A pride","A gang"],"question":"What is the word for a group of geese?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Dunkirk","incorrectAnswers":["Calais","La Havre","Dieppe"],"question":"From which French port did 200,000 British troops flee in 1940?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Christopher Tolkien","incorrectAnswers":["Neil Gaiman","J. R. R. Tolkien","J. K. Rowling"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Book of Lost Tales'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Thomas Edison","incorrectAnswers":["Gregory Pincus","Alexander Graham Bell","James Watt"],"question":"Which influential inventor and businessman helped introduce electricity and electric light bulbs?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Beyoncé","incorrectAnswers":["Madonna","Drake","Nicki Minaj"],"question":"Which American singer released the song 'Drunk in Love'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"John F. Kennedy","incorrectAnswers":["John Adams","Dwight Eisenhower","Lyndon Johnson"],"question":"Who was the 35th president of the USA, in term during the period 1961–1963?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Striptease","incorrectAnswers":["Showgirls","Basic Instinct","Indecent Proposal"],"question":"What is the name of the 1996 film starring Demi Moore about a woman who is short on funds and clothes?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Harland & Wolff","incorrectAnswers":["Myers Maritime","J.K. Thomson & Sons","Merl Systems"],"question":"Which shipbuilding company constructed the Titanic?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"North Carolina","incorrectAnswers":["Virginia","South Carolina","Georgia"],"question":"In what state did black sit-ins at segregated lunch counters first start in 1960?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Cow","incorrectAnswers":["A Jill","A Vixen","A Tigeress"],"question":"What is a female manatee known as?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Uzbekistan","incorrectAnswers":["Norway","Libya","Croatia"],"question":"In which country would you find the city of Bukhara?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Gothenburg","incorrectAnswers":["Frankfurt","Leipzig","Helsinki"],"question":"Which of these cities is in Sweden?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Silverstone","incorrectAnswers":["Brands Hatch","Thruxton","Knockhill"],"question":"At Which Course Is The British Grand Prix Held?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"1803","incorrectAnswers":["1776","1844","1895"],"question":"What year did the United States purchase the Louisiana Territory from France?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"John Travolta","incorrectAnswers":["Ralph Fiennes","Brian Cox","Michael Douglas"],"question":"Which actor has featured in films including Pulp Fiction and Hairspray?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Audrey Hepburn","incorrectAnswers":["Bette Davis","Catherine Deneuve","Selena Gomez"],"question":"Which actress has starred in films including Roman Holiday and Breakfast at Tiffany's?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Unemployment Rate","incorrectAnswers":["Jobless Rate","Inflation Rate","Labour Rate"],"question":"What is the term for the rate at which people without jobs are looking for work?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"dreams","incorrectAnswers":["drug dosage","the interrelationship between an organism's physical functioning and its environment","crop circles"],"question":"What is Oneirology the study of?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The Falklands War","incorrectAnswers":["The Irish War","The Vietnam War","The Gibraltan War"],"question":"Which War Involving The UK Began In 1982?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"One Direction","incorrectAnswers":["Boyzone","Backstreet Boys","Blur"],"question":"Which band did Harry Styles start his career with?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Robben Island","incorrectAnswers":["Bishop Island","Truncheon Island","Carril Island"],"question":"Where was Nelson Mandela held in prison?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"It is used in used in military shells, bombs, and grenades.","incorrectAnswers":["It is used in nuclear reactors, as a neutron moderator.","It is used in disinfectants and antiseptics.","It is known to relieve pain and inflammation."],"question":"What is the chemical trinitrotoluene often used for?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Sweden","incorrectAnswers":["Denmark","Germany","Kingdom of the Netherlands"],"question":"Which of these countries borders Norway?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Laslo Biro","incorrectAnswers":["Franz Bic","Henry Sheaffer","Pièrre Montblanc"],"question":"Who invented the ballpoint pen?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"One Direction","incorrectAnswers":["Level 42","Orchestral Manoeuvres in the Dark","Blur"],"question":"Which English-Irish boy band released the studio album 'Up All Night'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Chris Columbus","incorrectAnswers":["Steven Spielberg","Woody Allen","Martin Scorsese"],"question":"Which director directed Harry Potter and the Chamber of Secrets?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Australia","incorrectAnswers":["New Zealand","Canada","Ireland"],"question":"Vegemite, a trademarked vegetable extract used as a food spread, is from which country?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Roxana","incorrectAnswers":["Claudia","Diana","Helen"],"question":"What was Alexander The Great's wife's name?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Frangelico","incorrectAnswers":["Absinthe","Disaronno","Moscatel"],"question":"Which hazelnut liqueur is named for the hermit monk who made it 600 years ago? ","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"The Sea","incorrectAnswers":["The Sky","Wine","Horses"],"question":"Poseidon was the Greek god of what?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Colour Blindness","incorrectAnswers":["Short Sightedness","Far Sightedness","Cataracts"],"question":"Which sight problem occurs in men far more than in women?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Wether","incorrectAnswers":["Cuz","Wat","Ewe"],"question":"What is a word for a castrated ram?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Dracula","incorrectAnswers":["'Salem's Lot","Carrie","World War Z"],"question":"In which book does 'Jonathan Harker' appear?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Buffalo soldiers","incorrectAnswers":["Traitors","Picketties","Kwoquois"],"question":"What name did the indians give the black soldiers that were fighting against them in the late 1800's?","difficulty":"medium"},